DIMITRIOS MISTRIOTIS

CONTACT

077 8535 6554, int: +4477 8535 6554

dimitrios@mistriotis.com

www.mistriotis.com

Sutton, Surrey, UK.

EDUCATION

MSc, Computer Science 08-09 King's College London (KCL)

BSc, Computer Science 98-03 Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB)

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science Immersive, General Assembly, London UK (Jun. 2017 – Aug. 2017)

Accelerator Academy, London UK (Sep. 2013 – Dec. 2013)

Oracle Certified Java Professional

Oracle Certified Java Associate

Microsoft Certified Partner

PROJECTS

Wrote a book on the social aspects of IT, "IT Archetypes"

Podcasting

Open source contributions, adopted an open source library: https://pypi.org/project/alt-profanity-check/

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Please refer to extended CV version in the following pages

PROFILE

I am a seasoned professional who brings a diverse skill set and a proven track record of success in technical and leadership roles. My expertise spans multiple programming languages, web development frameworks, and cloud platforms. Throughout my career, I have honed my leadership abilities by managing development teams, mentoring colleagues, and excelling in project management.

Recently exited and transitioned a startup I co-founded, where I lead its technical development and scaling. I am committed to continuous learning, ensuring I stay at the forefront of technology trends.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Short Contract - Tech Lead

Bilt Renovation London, UK

Feb. 2023-June 2023

Bringing Residential Home Construction To The 21st Century." Running IT Department building applications and PoCs aiming to explore how to digitize and renovate within the industry.

Worked on Web platform's first version, interfaced with contractors to establish branding and lead capturing forms. Created functional Proof of Concepts for different functions using OpenAI and similar tools.

Technical environment: ChatGPT, OpenAl, MongoDB, Terraform, Docker, AWS, Fly.io, PostgreSQL, Python, Django, Tailwind, HTMX.

CTO/Tech Lead - Sr Manager

ID Shield, Oklahoma, USA - Sr. Manager Yourself Online, Inc. London, UK/Austin, USA - CTO/Tech Lead Nov. 2021-Feb. 2023 Mar. 2018-Nov. 2021

Build the technical aspect of a company from initial discussion up to product, pivots, expansion, acquisition. Post-acquisition integrated it to the new parent company's offering, scaling it for potential 1 Million users while extending it to different sectors and markets while adding features to the main product.

- Architecture, development, DevOps of product starting from a handwritten specification document
- Managing of the tech/development team plus contractors, and interns
- Assisting in investment, and sales efforts, liaising with different business stakeholders
- Created IP in the form of datasets and custom models
- Integrated platform with a number of different providers and systems

Technical environment: Python, Django, Celery, TailwindCSS, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Social Network Integrations, Google Cloud, Gitlab CI/CD, Pandas, Sklearn, ElasticSearch, Github Actions.

Technical Solutions Consultant

Google. London, UK

June 2015-Jan. 2018

Worked as part of an innovation team embedded in London's Large Customer Sales department. Prototyped and scaled solutions for local and global Industry Analysts. Was a member of gTech, company's consulting arm at the time.

- Export Tool: Developed, managed and extended tool for monitoring large customers
 export effort helping in generation of millions in revenue. Later on responsible for
 the whole of the tool from data gathering to user interface, integrations with other
 tools, collateral generation.
- Hotel Ads Spotlight: First project; build UI so that the project could be released. Data exploration for Hotels related metrics for specific markets
- Science of Search: Wrote a drop in replacement for a tool scheduled to be outphased. Allowed sales teams to continue operations for an additional year
- Audience Tool: Main contributor for development of an internal tool for surfacing search audience behaviour. Awarded with internal "Simplementation Superhero Awards" for 1st half of 2017
- · Volunteering: startups mentoring, coaching on getting into the software industry

Technical environment: Plex/Dremel, Borg, GoogleSQL, BigQuery, Angular, D3, JavaScript, AppsScript, Python, Java, Lua, GoogleSuite programming.

DIMITRIOS K. MISTRIOTIS

CONTACT DETAILS

Location: Sutton, Surrey, UK. **Email:** dimitrios@mistriotis.com

Mobile: 077 8535 6554, int: +4477 8535 6554

Website: https://www.mistriotis.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb. 2023 - June 2023: Bilt Renovation London, UK - Short Contract - Tech Lead

"Bringing Residential Home Construction To The 21st Century." Running IT Department building applications and PoCs aiming to explore how to digitize and renovate within the industry.

Worked on Web platform's first version, interfaced with contractors to establish branding and lead capturing forms. Created functional Proof of Concepts for different functions using OpenAI and similar tools.

Technical environment: ChatGPT, OpenAI, MongoDB, Terraform, Docker, AWS, Fly.io, PostgreSQL, Python, Django, Tailwind, HTMX.

Nov. 2021 – Feb. 2023: ID Shield, Oklahoma, USA - Sr. Manager, Product Eng. for Reputation Management Mar. 2018 – Nov. 2021: Yourself Online, Inc. London, UK/Austin, USA – CTO/Tech Lead

Build the technical aspect of a company from initial discussion up to product, pivots, expansion, acquisition. Post-acquisition integrated it to the new parent company's offering, scaling it for potential 1 Million users while extending it to different sectors and markets while adding features to the main product.

- Architecture, development, DevOps of product starting from a handwritten specification document
- Managing of the tech/development team plus contractors, and interns
- Assisting in investment, and sales efforts, liaising with different business stakeholders
- Created IP in the form of datasets and custom models
- Integrated platform with a number of different providers and systems

Technical environment: Python, Django, Celery, TailwindCSS, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Social Network Integrations, Google Cloud, Gitlab CI/CD, Pandas, Sklearn, ElasticSearch, Github Actions.

June 2015 - Jan. 2018: Google. London, UK - Technical Solutions Consultant, gTech Ads

Worked as part of a prototyping and innovation team embedded in London's Large Customer Sales department, where prototyped and scaled solutions for local and global Industry Analysts. Was a member of gTech (Google Professional Services), company's consulting arm.

- Export Tool: Developed, managed and extended tool for monitoring large customers export effort
 helping in generation of millions in revenue. Later on responsible for the whole of the tool from data
 gathering to user interface, integrations with other tools, collateral generation. Awarded with a "Sector
 Innovation" award and spot bonuses
- Hotel Ads Spotlight: First project; build UI so that the project could be released. Data exploration for Hotels related metrics for specific markets
- Science of Search: Wrote a drop in replacement for a tool scheduled to be outphased. Allowed sales teams to continue operations for an additional year until introduction of successor tool
- Audience Tool: Main contributor for development of an internal tool for surfacing search audience behavior. Awarded with internal "Simplementation SuperHero Awards" for 1st half of 2017
- Volunteering: startups mentoring, coaching people on how to get into the software industry

Technical environment: Plex/Dremel, Borg, GoogleSQL, BigQuery, Angular, D3, JavaScript, AppsScript, Python, Java, Lua, GoogleSuite programming.

Mar. 2014 - May 2015: HomeServe Alliance. London, UK - Senior Developer, Tech Lead

In the first months extended the company's web platform working on internal custom CMS. Was then assigned to the "Connected Home" division which orchestrated installation of smart devices from a licensed installer, such as Nest and Tado.

- Responsible for getting a system not fit for purpose which had to be repurposed while in use
- Created road-maps and oversaw their implementation after discussions with internal clients and management
- Chanced feature velocity by simplifying its surface and eliminating redundant dependencies
- Changed processes, introduced CI/CD, release management and other automations
- Re-architect of the application while used by hundreds of users with minimum disruption

Technical environment: RubyOnRails, JS/CoffeeScript, Rspec, Heroku, Micro-Services, Sidekiq.

June 2013 - Jan. 2014: Cypsel. London, UK - Co-founder, CTO, Tech Lead - Startup

Cypsel was an online marketplace where people that wanted to learn an art or an instrument could pair up with willing-to-teach artists.

- Architected, implemented, troubleshoot platform from ground up
- Managed integrations with other systems such as Facebook, Video calls
- Communications, Promotion, Pitching, Pricing Strategy, Contractor and volunteer management

Technical environment: Angular, Bootstrap, CoffeeScript, Golang, Heroku, Ruby on Rails.

Mar. 2012 - Jun. 2013: OpenBet. London, UK - Senior Developer

OpenBet Ltd is a provider of gaming and betting solutions. Engaged in consulting projects and the company's productization effort. Worked alongside different QA, testing, management, clients.

- Extended internal web offering for telephone betting
- Participated in rewriting of the company's back end core server

Technical environment: TCL, JavaScript, JavaEE, Different web technologies, Shell Scripting.

Jan. 2011 - Mar. 2012: Accenture. London, UK - Senior Developer, Java Solutions

Joiner training/certification, then in Client Information Services for the Dept. of Work and Pensions.

- Incident management, data repairs, service requests, process automation projects
- Application maintenance, internal tools development
- Helped evaluate Ruby on Rails and scripting languages curriculum

Technical environment: Java, Oracle PLSQL, ClearCase, Shell Scripting, Ruby on Rails.

Sep. 2009 – June 2010: Notion Learning. London, UK – CoFounder, Lead Developer

Notion Learning was a start-up which offered a SaaS solution to the e-learning sector. Architectural design, full stack development, stakeholder management, pricing, pitching, presenting. Technical environment: PHP, PostgreSQL, Subversion, JavaScript, Apache, FogBugs.

Feb. 2008 - Aug. 2008: Just In Time Advertising, Athens, Greece - Web Dev and Admin - Contract

Aug. 2007 - May 2008: MySapient Ltd, London, UK - Network and Web Developer - Remote Contract

Jan. 2007 - Sep. 2007: Care Direct, Athens, Greece - Software Developer

Feb. 2005 - Jul. 2006: Reserve 2nd Lieutenant - Greek Military, Field Artillery - Military Service

Oct. 2003 – June 2004: Tutor – Various state institutes of vocational education in Greece

EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS

Jan 2018 - Feb 2018: Functional Programming Principles in Scala, École Polytechnique de Lausanne

Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017: Data Science Immersive, General Assembly, London UK

Sep. 2013 - Dec. 2013: Accelerator Academy, London UK

Sep. 2008 - Sep. 2009: MSc, Computer Science, King's College London, Computer Science

Sep 1998 – June. 2003: BSc, Computer Science, Athens University of Economics and Business, Department of Computer Science

Oracle Certified Java Professional, Oracle Certified Java Associate, Microsoft Certified Partner.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Promoting/Rewriting a book on the social aspects of IT - www.itarchetypes.com, Running a Podcast around 8 years on different subjects including IT, career, and living abroad. Open source contributions, adopted an open source library: https://pypi.org/project/alt-profanity-check/